

# ISLEM BOUCHAALA

Third-year Telecommunications Engineering student

Looking for a 4 to 6 months internship in DevOps

islem.bouchaala@enetcom.u-sfax.tn

in www.linkedin.com/in/islem-bouchaala/

+216 55 860 821

Sfax, Tunisie



Having a quick adaptability and ready to tackle technical challenges will allow me to gain valuable professional experience. My goal is to actively contribute to DevOps-oriented projects, while enhancing my skills and bringing added value to the host company.



## ) PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- DevOps :
  - Docker
  - Kubernetes
  - GitLab CI/CD
  - Ansible
- Cloud Computing : Huawei, Azure
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- **▶** Programming:
  - JAVA
  - Python
  - C
- Web Development:
  - HTML, CSS, JS, PHP
  - Bootstrap
- Frameworks and Libraries :
  - ReactJS
  - Angular
  - SpringBoot
  - NodeJS
- Database:
  - ORACLE
  - MySQL
- Modeling: UMLOS: Windows, GNU/LINUX
- Maria Mathadalana
- Work Methodology :
  - Scrum
  - Lean Six Sigma
- Graphic Design:
  - Adobe Illustrator
  - Adobe XD



- ► Introduction to DevOps ( Docker & Kubernetes ) ( CrocoCoder ) | 03/2023
- ReactJS ( CrocoCoder ) | 12/2022Introduction to Angular (CSF)|02/2022
- LANGUAGES

French: ProficientEnglish: FluentSpanish: Basic

## **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

#### National School of Electronics and Telecommunications of Sfax

Field: Telecommunications Engineering

**CLASSES PREPARATOIRES, IPEIS** 

Field: Mathematics-Physics | 2019 - 2021

**Pionier High School of Sfax** 

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics with Honors

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## DevOps Internship: SPARK-IT

06/2023-07/2023

2021 - 2024

2015 - 2019

Optimization of software development processes : continuous integration, deployment, and orchestration of Stark application.

- ▶ Implemented and optimized containerization for application modules using Docker.
- ▶ Established a robust CI/CD pipeline with GitLab CI/CD, including a Build Stage for compiling and packaging projects, a Test Stage utilizing SonarQube to ensure high coding standards, and a Deploy Stage.
- ▶ Configured Kubernetes Deployment for modules to ensure optimal scaling.
- Defined Kubernetes Services to efficiently expose and access application modules.
- ▶ Ensured seamless application execution by configuring Pods within the Kubernetes environment.

Technologies: Docker, GitLab CI/CD, Kubernetes, SonarQube

#### Final Year Project: Web Application TunMedCare

01/2023-04/2023

Development of a functional online medical application for patients with chronic diseases, facilitating their communication with doctors and improving their health management.

- ▶ Implemented the front-end with ReactJS using TypeScript.
- ▶ Implemented the back-end with NodeJS and Express using JavaScript.

Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MangoDB, PostMan

#### Operator Internship: Tunisie Télécom

06/2022

- Operator internship in the Customer Service Center (CSC)

  Addressed and resolved operational disruptions to ensure smooth workflow.
- Executed various office tasks to support daily operations.

### **CERTIFICATES**

▶ Microsoft : Microsoft Azure Fundamentals AZ-900

09/2023

► Cisco : CCNAv7 Introduction to Networks

05/2022

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- ▶ Winner of the 2023 IEEE Women in Engineering Student Branch Affinity Group of the Year Award.
- Winner of the 1st prize in the IEEE Student-Teacher and Research Engineer/Scientist (STAR) Program, Tunisia Section.

#### **ASSOCIATIVE LIFE**

#### **ENET'Com Telecom Day v1.0**

01/2023

Marketing Manager

▶ Created the graphic design for the 1st edition of the Telecom Day event.

#### **IEEE ENET'Com Student Branch**

2022-2023

IEEE Women In Engineering (WIE) Marketing Manager

- ► Created the graphics for the 1st edition of the WIE ACT 1.0 event.
- ▶ Created the graphics for the STAR Program competition.